AI DevKit is an operating model for AI-centric software engineering.
AI writes specs, tests, code, and docs.
Humans approve the spec and approve the release.
It works with your existing stack — git,
repos, pull requests, continuous integration — and reshapes it around
AI execution, while keeping the human checkpoints that matter.
There are four pillars: spec planning,
test-driven implementation, Progressive Disclosure docs, and the AI
dev environment.
Work comes in as a story,
epic, bug, or feature.
It flows through three phases: Plan,
Implementation, and Release.
The Lead AI executes the workflow.
The Verify A.I.
independently reviews all Lead AI work — it's a second AI
from a different training lineage.
Why two AIs?
A single AI is confidently wrong in ways invisible to itself.
Asking the same model to review its own output rarely catches the
error.
Two independent lineages catch different mistakes.
The Plan phase produces a spec.
The Implementation phase produces working code,
tests, and updated docs.
That deliverable passes through Release — continuous integration and delivery
pipelines plus human approval.
Plan turns a work item into an approved spec.
The Lead AI reads the requirement,
the docs, and the code, then drafts a spec with acceptance criteria,
edge cases, and approach decisions.
The Verify A.I.
reviews the spec independently.
If the two AIs disagree on what a criterion means,
that's ambiguity — and it gets surfaced to the human before any
code is written.
The key discipline here: decide in the spec,
not in the code.
If you let the AI defer decisions to implementation,
it makes them implicitly, often inconsistently,
and you only find out when you're reading the code.
The phase ends when the human signs off.
Implementation turns the approved spec into working code.
The Verify A.I.
authors the failing tests directly from the spec.
The Lead AI writes the implementation to make them pass.
This is independent test authorship — the AI that writes the tests
is not the AI that writes the code.
Without that separation, implementation assumptions get silently baked into the tests.
After TDD completes, the Lead AI updates the Progressive Disclosure docs,
and the Verify A.I.
checks the updates against the actual code.
Then the spec is archived.
The docs carry everything forward.
Progressive Disclosure docs give every repo the same structure.
The same eight files, in every repo,
across the whole organisation.
Level zero is an identity card — what is this repo?
Level one is eight fixed files:
setup, architecture, code map, conventions, workflows,
interfaces, gotchas, and security.
Level two is deep dives, loaded only when Level one isn't enough.
Levels zero and one load upfront — they're small.
Level two is pulled in only when needed.
The agent gets full context without filling the context window.
That consistency is what lets any agent pick up any repo and
work safely.
Real systems span multiple repos — an API,
an SDK, a frontend, shared infrastructure.
The AI dev environment gives you one workspace where the AI can
run the whole system end to end.
It's a container of containers.
Each component runs in its own container,
all inside one outer workspace.
The Lead AI can start, stop,
restart, and test any component from there.
It runs locally or in the cloud.
Cloud workspaces are useful for team handoff — another engineer picks up
the same workspace and the same context.
The environment includes Playwright for browser testing and Terraform for infrastructure.
And there's an audit trail across all agent sessions — reproducibility,
traceability, and evals for debugging agent behaviour.
Everything in AI DevKit runs through six markdown files in a prompts
folder.
spec, implement, create docs, update docs,
verify with Codex, verify with Claude.
They're plain text — you can read them,
understand exactly what the AI is being told to do,
and modify them.
Why not skills or slash commands?
There are lots of ways to load instructions into an AI tool
— user settings, project files, enterprise configs,
skills, slash commands.
It's a walled garden.
A Claude skill doesn't work in Cursor.
A Cursor command doesn't work in Codex.
But at the end of the day,
it's all just text hitting an LLM.
Prompts are portable — you can paste them into any agent,
or pipe them from the command line.
Curl the prompts straight from GitHub — no clone needed.
For example: curl create-docs and verify-codex,
pipe to claude.
Or flip it — curl create-docs and verify-claude,
pass to codex.
Either way, one command generates Progressive Disclosure docs and runs
cross-model verification — end to end,
about fifty minutes, zero human intervention.
Visible prompts are accountable.
Hidden skills may or may not be followed.
Engineers should read the prompts, not trust hidden instructions.
Here's how to start.
Pick one repo.
Curl create-docs, pipe to claude — or pass to codex.
That's it — any agent can then pick up that repo and
work safely.
Chain verify-codex or verify-claude for cross-model review — works
in either direction.
The repo, the standard, and all the prompts are open at github.com/AgoraIO-Community/ai-devkit.